#### Contact

mdees@iuhealth.org

www.linkedin.com/in/mandy-dees-62460033 (LinkedIn)

## Top Skills

Nursing

Hospitals

Healthcare

## Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)

### Certifications

Nursing Professional Development CCRN-K

# Mandy Dees

Manager Nursing Education at IU Health - AACN Chapter Advisor - ANPD EBP Academy Mentor

Indianapolis, Indiana

# Summary

Accomplished Nursing Leader with over twenty years of demonstrated progressive leadership experience within the non-profit environment. Proven ability in leading teams, improving quality patient care, supporting best practice implementation, and modeling professionalism.

Areas of expertise: Performance Improvement – Curriculum

Development – Project Management – Change Management – Team

Building – American Association of Critical-Care Nurses Chapter

Advisor – Association for Nursing Professional Development EBP

Academy Mentor. Research professional pursuing a Doctor of

Philosophy (PhD) focused in Palliative Care integration within ICU

environments from Indiana University.

# Experience

Indiana University Health 10 years 7 months

Manager Nursing Education
June 2016 - Present (4 years 1 month)

University Hospital

Manage inpatient unit educators consistent with organizational policies and values.

Participate in the ongoing professional development of bedside nurses.

Report to Associate Chief Nursing Officer, provide input for strategic alignment of the clinical education department.

Interim Manager Nursing Education November 2015 - June 2016 (8 months)

Manage inpatient unit educators consistent with organizational policies and values. Report to Associate Chief Nursing Officer monthly; provide input for strategic alignment of the clinical education department.

Clinical Nurse Educator

December 2009 - November 2015 (6 years)

Methodist Hospital

Provide opportunities in support of professional development for all nursing levels. Impart knowledge using multiple modalities, including simulation. Partner with other clinical educators and nursing leadership to assess, develop, and evaluate programs to enhance life long learning.

IU Health, Methodist Hospital

**RN Partner** 

August 2006 - December 2009 (3 years 5 months)

Fulfilled charge nurse role by maintaining daily unit operations. Preceptor for new employees. Participated in systemwide committees. Interim clinical educator for two units.

IU Health, Methodist

7 years 9 months

Associated RN Partner

March 1999 - August 2006 (7 years 6 months)

Preceptor to new hires, participated in unit committees, trained to perform the charge nurse role.

Student Nurse Extern

December 1998 - March 1999 (4 months)

Assist nurses with care of critically ill patients.

## Education

Indiana University–Purdue University Indianapolis

PhD, Nursing Science · (2019 - 2024)

University of Indianapolis

Master, Nursing Education · (2010 - 2013)

University of Indianapolis

Bachelor of Science (BS), Nursing Science (2006 - 2009)

Indiana State University

Associate of Science (AS), Nursing Science · (1995 - 1998)